A Guide to the Atcheson Laughlin Hench Papers
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Atcheson Laughlin Hench Papers 1912-1962
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
416-b
This addition to the Atcheson Laughlin Hench Papers consists of ca. 1500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The Atcheson L. Hench Papers were a gift from Mrs. Oscar W. Underwood, III, his daughter, on 1 January 1975.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the Atcheson Laughlin Hench papers consists mainly of examinations and quizzes for various courses taught by Hench from 1912 to 1962. Most of the exams are for literature courses in Chaucer from 1923 to 1962; Old English, from 1925 to 1962; and Middle English, from 1924 to 1956 at the University of Virginia. Also included are exams in English Renaissance Poetry, 1932, and Shakespeare's Comedies, from 1928 to 1932. Two early exams, 1912 and 1913, are probably from Lafayette College as Hench taught there from 1912 to 1914.
Arrangement
The examinations and quizzes are arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- Exams and quizzes for English 11-12, Chaucer 1946-1951 (Box 1)
  ca. 120 items
- Exams and quizzes for English 11-12, Chaucer 1951-1952 (Box 1)
- Exams and quizzes for English 11-12, Chaucer 1956-1960 (Box 1)
  ca. 90 items
- Chaucer Examinations, English 109-110 1950-1962 (Box 1)
  ca. 40 items
- Examinations for Hench's Chaucer class, English 109-110 1950-1962 (Box 1)
  20 items
- Exams and quizzes for Chaucer course, English B-1 1929-1938 (Box 1)
  ca. 70 items
- Exams and quizzes for Chaucer Course, English B-1 ca. 1925-1941 (Box 2)
  ca. 105 items
- Exams and quizzes for Chaucer Course, English B-1 1942-1949 (Box 1)
- Exams and quizzes for Chaucer Course, English C-5 1923-1934 (Box 2)
  ca. 30 items
- Exams and quizzes for Chaucer Course, English C-5 1935-1939 (Box 2)
  ca. 36 items
- Exams and quizzes for Chaucer Course, English C-5 1940-1949 (Box 2)
  ca. 55 items
- Summer School Chaucer Examinations 1929-1942 (Box 2)
  34 items
- Examinations and quizzes for Chaucer in Translation 1943-1952 (Box 3)
  51 items
- Examinations for Hench's course, English B-2 1924-1928 (Box 3)
  ca. 125 items
- Examinations for Hench's English course, English B-3 1923-1926 (Box 3)
  ca. 50 items
- Examinations for Hench's course, English B-4 1928-1931 (Box 4)
  ca. 92 items
- Examinations for Hench's course, English B-4 1932-1934 (Box 3)
  ca. 110 items
- Examinations for Hench's course, English B-4 1935-1936 (Box 3)
  ca. 75 items
- Examinations for Hench's course, English B-10 1937 (Box 3)
  11 items
- English Literature C-1 exam; Wilson's course 1926 March 20 (Box 3)
  1 item
- Examinations for English Renaissance Poetry 1932 (Box 3)
  4 items
- Exam for History 7, Late Colonial Period to the Confederation 1947 (Box 3)
- Examinations for Hench's course, Middle English 1924-1932 (Box 3)
- Examinations for Hench's course, Middle English 1933-1956 (Box 3)
  ca. 35 items
- Miscellaneous examinations collected by A.L. Hench, mainly from Harvard 1912-1919 (Box 4)
  23 items
- Miscellaneous examinations for A. L. Hench's advanced degree candidates ca. 1935-1944, n.d. (Box 4)
  ca. 85 items
- Examinations for Hench's course, Old English 1925-1934 (Box 4)
  ca. 81 items
- Examinations for Hench's course, Old English 1935-1945 (Box 4)
  ca. 61 items
- Examinations for Hench's course, Old English 1946-1962 (Box 4)
  ca. 54 items
- Examinations for Hench's course, Shakespeare's comedies 1928-ca. 1932, n.d. (Box 4)
  35 items